This is incredible. Researchers have
built synthetic neurons that behave like
ours. They respond to dopamine. This
could interface with our own neurons. It
can interface with living tissue. Or it
could build a robot with a nervous
system that functions just like ours.
We'll talk about it. In the last few
years, researchers have been trying to
make functional synthetic neurons. This
can heal spinal damage. It could
reconnect neurons and allows them to
have a chance to communicate with each
other so they can grow. When researchers
are creating synthetic neurons to
interface with our own, they have to be
able to give the correct electrical
output. And that needs to be controlled
under biological conditions. They
created insulated graphine nanopiber
tubules that can create electrical
output just from the same concentration
gradient that our very own nervous
system uses. We don't really have a
computer that's sending out electrical
impulses to get it just right. I mean,
we kind of do in our brains. It doesn't
always do a very good job. It also has
to be able to act as a meristster. So it
needs to remember the voltage that
travels along it which graphine nanop
fibers can accomplish for our brains.
When you have electricity traveling
through your neurons, they have to
remember the signal. It gets
strengthened when that signal is found
more often. And that's just what these
can do. They were able to interface the
synthetic neurons with cardiomyio. So
heart tissue. You could imagine that
this technology could result in a
synthetic heart, one that can be printed
just for you. Now there is one part of
it that is biological. They borrowed
microtubules from bacteria. Geobacttor.
This allows them to have very thin tubes
that are actually flexible which a body
does need to be. They also lined it with
graphine and had insulation on the
outside. Now there is one major
component that needs to be the next step
and that's having something that's
capable of healing. If you're just going
to put it inside of a person and you're
expecting for their anatomy to
compensate, then yeah, it could be a
piece of hardware. But if it's going to
be standalone, if it's going to make up
the nervous system of a robot, it will
need to heal itself. And there's been a
lot of research towards self-healing
polymers, little nanobots that can lock
themselves together or notice when
there's damage. But the really cool
thing about that is there's no reason
that it can't be done. This research is
being done in polymer sciences. Imagine
an artificial nervous system for a robot
that's sculpted into an entire brain.
And that is what this technology is
ultimately working towards. That's why
brain organoids are used as an
alternative to traditional computation
because they use less power. So do
these. A synthetic brain organoid is not
outside of the question. And if a
synthetic brain organoid isn't out of
the question, then a synthetic brain
isn't either. This could really be our
path towards truly intelligent machines.
This isn't just borrowing from nature.
This is plagiarizing nature, which
you'll always hear me say, I think it's
the best way to go about it. Nature had
millions of years to evolve our systems.
Billions, in fact. Why not borrow from
what already works through trial and
error? Cuz we don't have to reinvent the
wheel. This is really exciting
technology for a wide variety of
reasons. Yes, artificial limbs, organs
perhaps, but also creating life,
consciousness. This could get us there.
It's just the start. And it is just the
start. Technology is improving faster
than any time in history. I believe that
it'll improve faster now. It did take
nature a while to figure out getting
from a neuron to getting to a whole
brain. This may be unethical. I'm not
really sure anymore. Either way, I will
be here to bring you more science news
on the bleeding edge. Also, if you want
resources, if you want any of the
materials used in the videos, they're
always directly linked in the
description. If you cannot access them
because of a payw wall, let me know.
There are ways.